### **Michael Gaydos**

420 S 40th St Boulder, CO 80305 203-331-5335 armakith@hotmail.com

### **SUMMARY**

Michael is an exceptional problem solver who strives to hold high standards and attention to detail in his work. He started his professional career as an avionics technician in the United States Air Force, maintaining military aircraft in a fast-paced active runway environment, and spent more than half of his career deployed overseas. After ten years of service and an honorable discharge, Michael has worked on a diverse range of electronics and engineering projects in the state of Colorado as a civilian, while also pursuing a degree in electrical engineering.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

University of Colorado - Boulder, Boulder, CO
Electrical and Computer Engineering Student

01/2024 - Present

Red Rocks Community College, Lakewood, CO Full-time College Student

05/2023 - 12/2023

Sierra Space, Louisville, CO Engineering Technician III (Contractor)

12/2022 - 04/2023

- Installs electrical harnesses, avionics components, and various flight/vehicle sensors for the Dream Chaser spacecraft "Tenacity" and "Shooting Star" cargo module.
- Utilizes CAD drawings and other engineering documentation in a Model-based manufacturing environment, and directly contributes to the improvement/evolution of manufacturing/engineering documentation and processes.
- Assembles electrical harnesses and avionics components in accordance with NASA Technical Standards as a certified IPC/WHMA-A-620D-S Space Addendum specialist.
- Enforces strict ESD protocols on the production floor, collaborates with teams to ensure a FOD free production environment, adheres to ISO class 8 cleanrooms, and contributes to a culture of work center safety awareness.

# Dept. of Transportation/National Park Service Traffic Program, Lakewood, CO Electronics/Traffic Technician (Contractor) 08/2021 – 12/2022

- Lead technician on a civil engineering team responsible for maintaining reliable traffic data collection from over 150 continuous traffic count stations located in 50 National Parks across 27 states.
- Maintained a broad range of traffic counting equipment to include induction loop, piezoelectric, pneumatic, radar, and telecommunication equipment in 120VAC or solar powered applications.
- Coordinated field inspections and travelled to remote locations to perform maintenance at National parks across the country.
- Researched and implemented network equipment and software to support various data collection methods, data uploading and maintaining the National traffic server database.
- Analyzed traffic data to provide valuable insight to the National Parks for civil engineering/infrastructure and social science applications.
- Provided technical support, training, and equipment dispatch for DOT, NPS, and 3<sup>rd</sup> party contractors on repairing, operating, inspecting, and installing those systems.

### Liteye Systems Inc., Centennial, CO Electronics/Production Technician

#### 09/2019 - 02/2021

- Manufactured, tested, repaired, and troubleshot optical devices for military applications to include: Infrared and video surveillance systems, helmet mounted display systems and weapon mounted optics.
- Assisted engineering team in research and development of aerial drone tracking/detection/radio frequency jamming system "Counter Unmanned Aircraft Systems (C-UAS) Defense Technology" valued at \$3.5 million dollars per unit.
- Assembled computer/server racks, power relay boxes, pneumatic antenna hoisting systems, and operator/control room for the C-UAS units.
- Adhered to and maintained safe ESD practices in the work center, and maintained clean room environments for optical components.

## Front Range Community College, Westminster, CO Full-time College Student

08/2018 - 08/2019

### Herc Rentals Inc., Henderson, CO B-mechanic/Service Technician

06/2017 - 07/2018

- Performed scheduled maintenance, mechanical repairs and troubleshot mechanical/ electrical issues for maintenance ground equipment, professional contracting tools, heavy construction vehicles, forklifts, man-lifts and on-road vehicles.
- Prioritized quick turn around times for servicing and repairing rental equipment in order to provide availability for customers, and trained them on equipment operation.
- Operated heavy equipment and loaded them onto vehicles for equipment haulers.
- Installed new vehicle components and performed inspections in response to service orders, recall actions and manufacturer instructions.
- Managed monthly safety inspections to reduce workplace hazards in accordance with ANSI safety protocols and enforced proper hazardous waste disposal procedures.

Minot State University, Minot, ND Full-time College Student

08/2016 - 05/2017

## United States Air Force - AFGSC, Minot AFB, ND Bomb/Nav Avionics Technician

05/2012 - 03/2016

- Performed supervision and maintenance duties for the 5th Maintenance Squadron Phase Inspection dock, Bomb/Nav Avionics section.
- Lead avionics technician, responsible for completion of the 450-hour periodic phase inspection and maintenance of 28 B-52H aircraft valued at \$2.8 billion dollars.
- Managed avionics COMSEC program, RF Monitoring program, and squadron equipment account program.
- Troubleshot and repaired military avionics, navigation, communications, and munition guidance systems down to component level, upgraded system software/firmware and modified aircraft systems in accordance with USAF technical orders.
- Performed general aircraft maintenance team functions within inspection hangars and active flight line environments to include: refueling, towing, jacking, and munition loading operations.
- Supervised, trained, lead, and completed performance reports for team members.

## United States Air Force - PACAF, Kadena Air Base, Japan Integrated Avionics Technician

10/2008 - 05/2012

- Performed supervision and maintenance duties for 718th Aircraft Maintenance Squadron Comm/Nav avionics section on 15 KC-135R/T aircraft valued at \$795 million dollars.
- Lead technician who performed flight line maintenance expediter duties and supervised shift avionics section to support maintenance of the aerial refueling squadron.
- Supervised, trained, lead, and completed performance reports for team members.
- Dependable team member on 24/7 Kadena Air Base aero-medical evacuation standby crew, transient aircraft program, and higher-headquarter mission crew.
- Deployed throughout Pacific/Asia theater as flying avionics/crew chief team member as directed by USAF higher-headquarter missions.
- Primary COMSEC/classified materials handling officer for 718th AMXS avionics section.

## United States Air Force - USAFE, RAF Mildenhall, England Integrated Avionics Technician

12/2006 - 10/2008

- Performed maintenance duties for 100th Aircraft Maintenance Squadron Comm/Nav avionics section on 15 KC-135R/T aircraft valued at \$794 million dollars.
- Troubleshot, inspected, repaired, installed military avionics, navigation, and communications systems aboard aircraft.
- Performed general aircraft maintenance, inspections, refueling/defueling, tow/jack, air-field marshalling/traffic procedures, and isochronal/periodic inspections of aircraft.
- Cross-trained in other maintenance shops such as electrical-environmental, guidance and control, hydraulics, and propulsion sections to assist other maintenance teams.
- Deployed throughout European/Middle East/African theater as flying avionics/crew chief team member as directed by USAF higher-headquarter missions.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Colorado - Boulder **2024** College of Engineering and Applied Science

Red Rocks Community College **2023**Pre-engineering transfer credits

Front Range Community College **2018 – 2019**Pre-engineering transfer credits

Minot State University 2016 – 2017 General education credits

### **ADDITIONAL CERTIFICATIONS**

- IPC/WHMA-A-620D-S Electronics Manufacturing with Space Addendum certified.
- FCC Ground Radiotelephone Operator License with RADAR endorsement holder.
- CPR/medical/operational security/communication security/workplace hazard training.
- Experienced with MacOS, Windows, Linux, C/C++, Python.
- Forklift, powered man lift, and other heavy equipment operator experience.
- Aerospace ground equipment operation.
- OSHA "10-Hour training" certification